# **Matthew Rowlandson**

# Senior Lead Software Engineer

"I am extremely passionate about my work and always give it my all. When given a project or task, I not only meet the requirements but strive to exceed expectations and deliver results that go above and beyond. I am committed to putting in the extra effort to ensure that everything I do is of the highest quality."

## **Professional Profile**

As a Team Lead Software Engineer with a strong background in full-stack development, I am a smart and driven professional with a broad range of technical and soft skills. My ability to multitask and learn quickly enables me to stay ahead of the curve and deliver high-performing solutions. I am known for my innovation and ability to work well in a team, as well as my strength in leadership alongside a team of developers. With my skills and expertise, I am confident in my ability to contribute highly to any project, building great software and a better business.

## Work Experience

# Augmentt Technology | Fully Remote (EST) | September 2020 - March 2024 Software Engineering Team Lead

"Providing technical direction and building complex software systems as a lead contributor to the Augmentt platform."

- Lead contributor to the Augmentt platform, having written a large portion of the fullstack using AWS [Serverless Lambda, S3, SQS, EC2, Cognito], NodeJS, ReactJS, mySQL, Git, NextJS, Elasticsearch. Testing using Jest, Cypress. Storybook for components.
- My focus is on building and improving scalable generic infrastructure/systems that other developers can use as a foundation for their work. Implemented Backend Testing suite using Jest.
- Led a team of 4 developers who worked to enhance the Augmentt platform. I led daily standups and provided technical leadership to the rest of the Engineering team over Microsoft Teams chats and 1:1 video meetings.
- In Jira, wrote or had part in writing technical stories and researching ways to enhance the
  platform. Grooming backlog tickets from the PM and design team and creating new tickets for
  platform improvements.
- When high-priority customer issues arise, I triage, delegate and have those issues resolved within support parameters. Ensuring measures to prevent similar issues from occurring in the future through monitoring and alerts.
- As a core voice on the Engineering team, I am vocal in giving feedback and direction on problem-solving and technical architecture, while mentoring and supporting my teammates.
- Running of Agile Scrum meetings (sprint planning, backlog refinements, retrospectives) and Share and Learns.
- Working in a decentralized but collaborative environment with other developers and contractors worldwide (EST, PST, AST, CET)

# **Matthew Rowlandson**

# Senior Lead Software Engineer

705) 331-5010 matt 94101@live.ca

Zaui Software | Remote (Freelance) | October 2019 - January 2020

### **Software Developer Consultant**

"Working remotely in EST timezone. Planning, designing and implementing software modules for Zaui's software platform."

Zaui Software | Vancouver, BC | October 2018 - July 2019

#### **Full Stack Software Developer**

"Working on a team of 8: implementing features, bug fixes and integrations with Zaui's large enterprise platform"

- PHP 7.2, MySQL
- JavaScript, jQuery, NodeJs
- CSS3, HTML
- Unit Testing via Codeception and PHPUnit

## gShift | Barrie, ON | September 2015 - June 2016

## **Intermediate Software Developer**

"Integrated a new multimillion dollar acquisition into a main ~2 million line enterprise level web application."

- Working alongside a team of 6 Developers and a Project Manager.
- Maintained and created new features for an enterprise level Ruby on Rails application.
- Effectively integrated a newly acquired company's software (Webcrawler built on AngularJS & NodeJS) into the main web application creating a new user interface and providing platform access via REST API.
- Other responsibilities included: feature design, documentation, agile development, automated deployment and unit/integration testing.

# One More Story Games | Barrie, ON | January 2014 - April 2015

## Senior Software Developer | Co-Founder and Team Leader

"Worked alongside the CEO/CTO and mentored team of junior developers while building fresh core features"

- Led a team of 8 student developers and created a data driven game platform for user generated interactive fiction content.
- Provided coaching, mentoring, and providing feedback to my team.
- Created on a PHP and mySQL back-end with an ActionScript 3 (Flash) front-end.
- Developed an e-commerce store with payments through Stripe, full main user interface, game flow and base game architecture and more.

# **Matthew Rowlandson**

# Senior Lead Software Engineer

# National Department of Defense | Borden, ON | May 2013 - August 2013 Technical Support Specialist

"Considered an excellent communicator and ideal candidate for a full time position as a live agent"

- Worked alongside a technical support team providing service to over 1000+ users across Base Borden.
- Responded to support tickets by providing on site service which included troubleshooting software and hardware issues.

#### Education

#### Trent University | 2016 - 2018 | Bc.S Computing Systems with Honours | 4Yr Degree | 82 GPA

"Extended my coding abilities to encapsulate complex theory and algorithms"

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Advanced software architecture
- Project Management
- Artificial Intelligence Theory "Capstone Team Project: Successfully developed Machine Learning system for predicting cryptocurrency prices."

## Georgian College | 2012 - 2015 | Computer Programmer Analyst with Honours | 3Yr | 86 GPA

"Developed strong coding skills and gained extensive hands on work experience through 3 Co-op work terms"

- Team Project: Developed hospitality employee management system (MEAN stack)
- Programming Languages (C#, Python, C++, JavaScript, Java, ASP.net)
- Databases: mySQL, MongoDB, MicrosoftSQL, DB2
- Web development fundamentals (CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, Ajax)

#### Technical Skills

Core Skillset: JavaScript (ReactJS, NodeJS, NextJS, AngularJS), HTML5, CSS/SCSS

Automated Testing (Jest, Mocha, Chai), Typescript, JSON, YAML, Python

**Software:** Git, Visual Studio Code, Jira, Confluence, Microsoft Teams, Slack

**Database/DBMS:** MySQL, Elasticsearch (ELK), MongoDB, Redis

**Operating Systems:** OSX, Windows, Ubuntu

**Dev Operations:** AWS (Serverless, Ec2), DigitalOcean, Bash, Cloudformation